davidgilmour.com 2016-06-08

# Privacy

We may combine Personal Information that you submit on or through the Property with information that we collect from and about you from other online and offline sources, including from our own websites and web properties (including apps, widgets and players) and third party sources, which may include social media services you interact with through our Properties. We treat such combined information as Personal Information as long as it is so combined. 

We will retain your Personal Information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law. 

We ask that you not send us, and you not disclose, any sensitive Personal Information (e.g., social security numbers, information related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religion or other beliefs, health, criminal background or trade union membership) on or through the Properties or otherwise to us. 

We and our third-party service providers may collect Other Information (defined above) such as: 

  * Browser and device information 
  * Mobile App usage data 
  * Server log files 
  * Information collected through cookies, pixel tags and other technologies. If you are located within the EEA please read our cookie policy <http://www.wminewmedia.com/cookies/> for further details on our use of cookies. 
  * Geographic location information 
  * Demographic information and other non-personally identifiable information 
  * Information about how you use the Properties 
  * Aggregated information 

**How We May Collect Other Information**

We and our third-party service providers may collect Other Information in a variety of ways, including: 

  * **Through your browser or your device:** Certain information is collected by most browsers, such as your Media Access Control (MAC) address, device type (Windows or Macintosh), screen resolution, operating system version, Internet browser type and version and the type and version of the Property that you are using. We and our service providers may also collect a unique device identifier assigned by us or our service providers to the device from which you are accessing the Property and other transactional information for the device that we and our service providers may use to serve content and advertisements to the device. 
  * **Through your use of Mobile Apps:** When you download and use a Mobile App, we and our service providers may track and collect Mobile App usage data, such as the date and time the Mobile App on your device accesses our servers and what information and files have been downloaded to the Mobile App based on your device number. 
  * **Through server log files:** An Internet Protocol (IP) address is a number that is automatically assigned to your device from which you are accessing the Property by your Internet Service Provider (ISP), and is identified and logged automatically in our server log files whenever you visit the Property, along with the time of the visit and the activity on the Property. We and our service providers use IP addresses for purposes such as calculating Property usage levels, helping diagnose server problems, administering the Property and determining your approximate geographic location. 
  * **Using cookies:** We and our service providers may use cookies, pixel tags, web beacons, Adobe Flash technology (including Flash Local Stored Objects (“ **Flash LSOs** ”)) and other similar technologies to, among other things, better serve you with more tailored information for our products and services, and for those of third parties, facilitate your ongoing access to and use of the Property, and collect and store information about your use of the Property. For example, pixel tags and web beacons may be used in connection with the Property to, among other things, track the actions of the Property users, measure the success of marketing campaigns and compile statistics about the Property usage and response rates. 
  * If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure on most devices through which the Properties are accessed that allows you to decline the use of cookies. To learn more about cookies, please visit <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/>. If you choose to decline cookies, then some or all of the features, functionality and promotions available through the Property that may not be available to you. 
  * If your device stores Flash LSOs, and if you do not want Flash LSOs stored on your device through which you access the Property, you can adjust the settings of your Flash player to block Flash LSO storage using the tools contained using the [Website Storage Settings Panel](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html). You can also control Flash LSOs by going to the [Global Storage Settings Panel](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager03.html) and following the instructions (which may include instructions that explain, for example, how to delete existing Flash LSOs (referred to as “information” on the Macromedia site), how to prevent Flash LSOs from being placed on your device without you being asked, and (for Flash Player 8 and later) how to block Flash LSOs that are not being delivered by the operator of the page you are on at the time). Please note that setting the Flash Player to restrict or limit acceptance of Flash LSOs may reduce or impede the functionality of some Flash applications, including, potentially, Flash applications used in connection with the Property or our content. We expect our service providers and technology suppliers to honor any decision by you to restrict or limit Flash LSOs, but we cannot guarantee that they will do so. 
  * The use of these technologies allows our third-party vendors to deliver advertisements about our products and services, and the products and services of third parties, when you use the Property or other applications or visit websites or web properties across the Internet. These vendors may place so-called “pixel tags,” “web beacons,” “clear GIFs” or similar technologies on the device through which you access the Property, and other applications or websites across the Internet, and also place or recognize third-party cookies when you use the Property, or other applications, websites or web properties. These vendors may use information about your visits to the Property, and other applications, websites or web properties (excluding your name, address, email address and telephone number) to provide advertisements for us and others about goods and services that may be of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please visit the Network Advertising Initiative at [www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) or the Digital Advertising Alliance at [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/). 
  * **Geographic location information:** If you use any location-enabled products or services, you may be sending us location information. When you use a location-enabled service, we may collect and process information about your precise geographical location, such as GPS signals sent by a mobile device. We and our third party service providers and partners may use your device’s physical location to provide you with personalized location-based services, content and advertisements. In some instances, you may be permitted to allow or deny such uses of your device’s location, but if you choose to deny such uses, we may not be able to provide you with the applicable personalized services and content. 
  * **From you:** We may collect demographic information, such as your zip code or gender, as well as other information, such as your preferred means of communication, when you voluntarily provide this information to us. Unless combined with Personal Information, this information does not personally identify you or any other user of the Properties. 
  * **Information about how you interact on the Properties:** We may collect information about how you interact on the Properties. For example, some Properties may utilize analytic tools to help us better serve you through improved products, services, and revisions to the Properties. This collected information may let us know which services and features you are using the most within a Property, as well as device type and hardware features, country and language of download, etc. 
  * **By aggregating information:** We may aggregate Personal Information so that the end-product does not personally identify you or any other user of the Property, for example, by using Personal Information to calculate the percentage of our users who like a particular artist. 

**How We May Use and Disclose Other Information**

Please note that we may use and disclose Other Information for any purpose, except where we are required to do otherwise under applicable law. If we are required to treat Other Information as Personal Information under applicable law, then we may use it as described in “How We May Collect Other Information” section above, as well as for all the purposes for which we use and disclose Personal Information. In some instances, we may combine Other Information with Personal Information (such as combining your name with your geographical location). If we combine any Other Information with Personal Information, the combined information will be treated by us as Personal Information as long as it is combined. 

**SECURITY**

We seek to use reasonable physical, technical and administrative measures to protect Personal Information under our control. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or data security system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. 

**CHOICES AND ACCESS**

**Your choices regarding our use and disclosure of your Personal Information**

We give you many choices regarding our use and disclosure of your Personal Information for marketing purposes. You may opt-out from: 

**Receiving marketing-related emails from us and our affiliates:** If you do not want to receive marketing-related emails from us and our affiliates on a going-forward basis, you may opt-out from receiving such emails either by using the unsubscribe mechanism provided in the email or by emailing us at [privacypolicy@wmg.com](mailto:privacypolicy@wmg.com). 

**Receiving marketing-related SMS text messages from us and our affiliates:** If you do not want to receive marketing-related SMS text messages from us and our affiliates on a going-forward basis, you may opt-out from receiving such messages by texting back “STOP” or by emailing us at [privacypolicy@wmg.com](mailto:privacypolicy@wmg.com). 

**Our sharing of your Personal Information with artists or unaffiliated third parties for their marketing purposes:** If you prefer that we not share your Personal Information on a going-forward basis with artists or unaffiliated third parties for their marketing purposes, you may opt-out from such sharing by emailing us at [privacypolicy@wmg.com](mailto:privacypolicy@wmg.com). 

In each case, please make clear in your email what you are opting-out from. We will try to comply with your request(s) as soon as reasonably practicable. 

Please note that, if you opt-out as described above, we will not be able to remove your Personal Information from the databases of our artists or unaffiliated third parties with which we have already shared your Personal Information as of the date that we implement your opt-out request. Please also note that, if you do opt-out from receiving marketing-related messages from us, we may still send administrative messages to you; you cannot opt-out from receiving administrative messages. 

**How you can access, change or suppress your Personal Information**

If you would like to review, correct, update, suppress, delete or otherwise limit our use of your Personal Information that you have previously provided to us, you may contact us by emailing us at [privacypolicy@wmg.com](mailto:privacypolicy@wmg.com). 

In your request, please make clear what Personal Information you would like to have changed and what limitations (if any) you would like to place on our use of your Personal Information. We will try to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable. We may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes, and there may also be residual information that will remain within our databases and other records which will not be removed. We are not responsible for changing, removing or suppressing information from the databases of artists or unaffiliated third parties with which we have already shared your Personal Information. 

**CONTACTING US**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us by email at [privacypolicy@wmg.com](mailto:privacypolicy@wmg.com), or please write to the following address: 

Warner Music UK Limited   
Legal Department   
The Warner Building   
27 Wrights Lane   
London   
W8 5SW   
Attn: Privacy Coordinator 

Please note that email communications are not always secure, so please do not include credit card information or other sensitive information in your email messages to us.
